Oh, boy. It's happening, huh?
The day has come for Maki-kun
to meet the full Umi family.
I'm sorry for your loss.
What?
Amami-san would usually
say something like...
Lucky you! I wish I could have
dinner at Umi's place, too!
So what gives?
Is Umi's dad that scary?
My dad isn't scary or anything, okay?
It's Riku you're afraid of, isn't it?
"Riku"?
Oh, your... older brother?
I'm afraid I don't recall.
Don't erase him from your memories!
I can't believe she's reacting like this
when she's friendly with everyone.
What is Umi's brother even like?
Good for you, though, Maki.
You've got family dinner this week
and the Christmas party the next.
I didn't register for the party,
so I won't get to go.
Wait, what?
Let's go talk to my sister and
see what we can do, then.
STUDENT COUNCIL OFFICE
Nozomu.
Why are you like this?
Wait, Nozomu's sister...
is the student council president?!
Look, I get that I'm asking
a lot out of nowhere.
Just tell me if you can or can't.
A bunch of people canceled, so we
do have the leeway, numbers-wise.
Hey, cool!
Add Maki's name to the list, then...
Ow!
I'm not done, you dunce.
Maehara-kun, was it?
First off, thanks for being
friends with my brother.
Don't mention it.
Anyway, I'm sorry for saying
I want in at the last minute.
You should be.
The student council policy prohibits
accepting requests after the deadline.
But one of our members can't make it,
and we do need a fill-in.
As staff, you won't get to
take part in any of the activities,
but you're free to eat there
during break time.
Thank you, Prez!
Let's go!
Yeah.
Good for you, Umi.
How so?
I'll get to spend Christmas with Umi!
This should do, right?
Thank you for inviting my son over.
Oh, no, feel free to tell him what's what.
Of course.
I'll send him on his way, then.
You didn't have to call them.
I know, but I felt like it.
I also wanted to talk to Sora-san again.
Mom, did Dad say something to you?
No. His messages are the same as always.
Mom.
Yeah, he found out the state
I'd gotten into at work.
He gave me a real earful.
I know I deserved it, too.
Mom hadn't told Dad about how busy work
at her publishing company had gotten.
When he found out,
he scolded her for it, saying,
"Why would you burden our son like that"?
But does he really have the right?
We can't really live our lives
unless you work.
Mom?
Wait, am I wrong?
Yeah. The truth is, I didn't have to
work at all to put food on the table.
Your dad sends us enough money
every month to cover it all.
Then why have you been paying for it?
It was a matter of pride.
I wanted to prove that I could handle things
without touching any of his money.
Also, work kept my mind
off of everything else.
I'm sorry, Maki.
We've selfishly put you through so much
and made you feel so alone.
But that all changes now.
We can't be a family of three anymore,
but I'll always be here for you,
even if nobody else is.
Anyway, we can talk about it later.
You should get going.
Welcome, Maki-kun!
Thanks for coming all this way.
No, thank you for inviting me.
This is from my mom. It's nothing special,
but she hopes you'll accept it.
My, thank you very much.
Now, come on in.
Th-Thank you for having me.
Are you gonna be okay, Maki? You look
like you're about to have a heart attack.
I-I'll be fine, probably.
Dad, Maehara Maki-kun's here.
Hello, Maehara-kun.
I'm Daichi, Umi's father.
I-I'm Maehara Maki.
Let me thank you for taking the time
to visit us during this busy time of year.
Also, thank you for looking out
for my daughter.
Not at all... Umi...
Wait, I mean...
Feel free to address her
the way you usually do.
She's in high school now.
It's not strange for her to have
a few male classmates she's close to.
Right...
Come on, dear. You're scaring Maki-kun.
Now, drop that tense expression
and smile for us!
Wh-What are you doing?
In front of our guest, too!
Help me out, Umi.
Roger.
S-Stop that!
M-Maehara-kun, tell these two off for me!
Wrong, dear. You mean "Maki-kun,"
not "Maehara-kun," right?
Maki-kun! Please!
Uh... Daichi-san can't take anymore.
You're still too stiff!
I'll loosen up as well,
so could you please let him go?
Stop it! Knock it off!
Yeah? Okay, Umi, you can stop now.
Got it.
Maki-kun, um, I apologize
for embarrassing myself like that.
Well, you see what we're like.
That's right. Isn't it fun?
Y-Yeah.
Mom, enough of the sketch comedy.
Can we get dinner started?
I'm starving.
Right you are.
Dear, could you get our son for me?
Sure.
What's your big brother like?
He's an unemployed shut-in.
Also, he's taken a massive liking to Yuu.
He started crawling towards her
this one time for no reason.
It was creepy as all heck.
Yeah...
I can see why she wants to avoid him.
Get down here, Riku.
Why are you sitting there?
We haven't had a guest over in ages.
I have to show him the trademark
Asanagi hospitality.
I'll handle that!
But then I wouldn't get
to have fun with him!
Umi, Mommy believes you
shouldn't keep him all to yourself.
I knew that was what you were after!
Mom, Umi.
Let's drop it there,
or your dad will tell us off.
Don't worry. I'll let you have
the privilege of feeding Maki-kun.
I-I'm not doing that!
You're so stupid, Mom!
Oh, right. Why don't we play some
games after we're done eating?
I got the latest entry in the series
we always play at your house.
Wait, you did? I so wanna play.
Okay, so we're battling after dinner.
So yeah, bro, we'll be using your room.
Don't just waltz into my sanctuary.
Also, that game's mine, not yours.
Come on, you can afford
to go outside for once.
Where exactly do you want me to go?
I dunno, the unemployment office?
Like it'd be open at this hour!
I know it's not. But you could easily
look up job listings on your phone.
Right, Dad?
Yes. You heard her, Riku.
Yes?
Make sure you go first thing on Monday.
Understood.
Sorry about that, Maki.
You're a guest, and you keep
having to watch us squabble...
Huh? What's the matter?
Wait, Maki, you haven't realized?
That smells good.
What's for dinner, Mom?
What could it be?
Try guessing, Maki.
Hamburg steak?
Hey, bingo.
You win a carrot glace
for getting it right.
What? I don't want carrot!
Too bad. You need to stop being picky
and eat your veggies,
or you'll never grow up big and strong.
I'm home.
Dad! Welcome back!
Hey, Maki. Were you a good boy today?
Yeah.
Don't let him fool you.
He was just whining about
not wanting to eat carrot.
Is this true?
That's not how a good boy behaves.
Fine, I'll eat it.
That's my son. Good boy.
You really love Dad, don't you?
Anyway, dinner's ready.
Let's eat together.
Yeah!
Back then, I thought those times
would last forever.
But around the time
I started middle school,
we gradually stopped
having dinners for three.
Dad sure is late.
Right? He even said he'd be home
at a reasonable time tonight.
I'm starting to get really hungry,
so let's go ahead and eat.
Otherwise, we won't get to
eat until midnight.
Yeah. I worked hard on tonight's dinner,
but it is what it is.
The Maehara family dining table
lost one member at first.
For a while after that,
it was just my mom and me...
But she grew quieter over time
as their marital issues intensified.
We were both eating at the same table,
but it felt like there was an invisible
wall separating the two of us.
And after my parents divorced,
I was the only one left at the table.
I... I'm so sorry.
Why is this happening? I didn't mean to...
Maki-kun?
H-Hey...
Are you okay?
Sorry, Umi.
I'm going to go get some
fresh air and calm down!
Wait, Maki!
Maki...
Ugh, what is wrong with me?
Why did I have to go and cry
in front of Umi's family?
I feel so embarrassed,
pathetic, and uncool.
I'm a high schooler now.
I'm not supposed to be such a baby!
Maki!
Umi?
I'll be back in a bit, so stay inside.
You moron!
Do you really think I can just stay put
after seeing my friend in that state?!
I get it, but I want
to be alone right now!
Shut up! Stop trying to run!
And let me take you into custody!
Gotcha.
You moron. Look at you.
Your face is a mess.
Sorry.
It's okay. Come on.
Come to me.
I'm so ashamed. I acted like a child.
We high schoolers
are still kids, you know.
We can get away with sniffling up to
someone like this. Just barely, I think.
Nobody else is here right now.
Nobody's going to make fun of you.
So stop worrying about it and
entrust yourself to me, okay?
I'm sorry.
I think you mean "thank you."
Right. Thank you, Umi.
The thing with your parents
was weighing on you after all?
Yeah. I thought I'd gotten
over it, but apparently not.
Oh... You did well to hang in there.
For now, forget about it all
and give yourself up to me.
You can think about it
after you get some good sleep,
eat a bellyful of food,
and feel like yourself again.
Okay.
Just go to sleep like that for tonight.
Good night, then.
Thanks.
Sure. Good night.
Maki, remember that
I'll always love you, okay?
Heya.
What time is it?
Just past eight. Good thing it's Saturday.
If you were awake,
you could've gotten out of bed.
I mean, I only woke up around an hour ago.
Watching your sleeping face
made the time fly by, so don't worry.
I dunno. It sounds like I have more
to worry about than I thought.
So, how'd it feel?
How'd what feel?
Sleeping on my lap like a baby.
Straight for the jugular, huh?
Do I have to say it?
It would make me happy if you did.
In that case, it was c-comfy...
And?
Warm...
Okay?
And it smelled good?
Perfect for a good night's sleep, then!
That makes it all worth it.
This is too one-sided.
I haven't done anything to deserve
you going out of your way for me.
You're wrong about that.
You've given me so much
you have no idea about.
In the time between us
becoming friends and now,
your kindness has given me
so much strength, so many times.
I only did what I did because
that's what you did for me.
That's all.
Umi...
Umi? Maki-kun?
What exactly do you think you're doing
first thing in the morning?
S-Sora-san?!
H-Hey, wh-what happened to knocking?
I did knock. Several times.
We need to have a talk
once we're done with breakfast.
Yes, ma'am.
Listen, I'm not going
to tell you not to kiss.
Just please, think about
the time and place.
I'm sorry.
If you don't, you'll cause
a whole mess like we did.
Honey?
Why am I catching strays here?
Are you? Maybe you're overthinking it?
Anyway, that's all I had to say.
Maki-kun, can we talk in private?
My wife and daughter told me a little
about your situation last night.
Uh, I'm really sorry for breaking down.
Don't worry about it.
That kind of thing is a lot to take in,
even for adults like ourselves.
It must've taken a huge toll on
a sensitive, gentle kid like you.
You did great holding on
by yourself, Maki-kun.
Thank you.
However, I do think you tried
a bit too hard to carry the burden.
It's not a bad thing to be considerate
of your parents and their divorce.
But that doesn't mean you have to
completely bottle up your feelings.
If you hold them in too long,
your mind will give out someday.
You should be able to understand that now.
Right.
Yeah, that dream I had over and over...
was because I had something
to say to both of them.
Well, even if I begged and pleaded,
it's not like my parents would make up
just to indulge me, right?
If it's too late to cry and complain,
I'd rather hold it in
than put them on the spot.
Yeah. As you say,
it won't change anything.
Then it really is pointless.
No, there is a point.
Huh?
If you cry, complain, and throw a tantrum,
it will get that load off your chest
if nothing else.
It's okay to be honest with yourself
and do what you want.
I'm back.
I'M OUT SHOPPING -MOM
She was going through the album?
This is such a good photo.
I wish we could go back.
It's okay to be honest with yourself
and do what you want.
I'm allowed to be more demanding.
MEMORIES ALBUM
MAEHARA FAMILY
Okay, I've decided.
It's almost Christmas Eve.
I'm going to take the day that marks
one year since Dad and Mom divorced...
CAN YOU DO ME A FAVOR?
and make it a line in the sand.
Translation: Sriram Gurunathan
Subtitle Editing: Geoff Mazzolini
Subtitle Timing: Krzysztof Kunc
Quality Check: Ashley Barboza
Translation Check: David Saylor
"One Last Tantrum."